National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records 5767
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records
1959-1970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Institute of Labor Education (NILE)
5767
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5702272
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 17, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5234: Inter-University Labor Education Committee Records 5545: National Institute of Labor Education (NILE) Papers 5944: National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records
National Institute of Labor Education (U.S.)
5702272
- Committee on Extension of Labor Education (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Federal Government Programs and Labor Education (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Final Report OMAT Project P 3-63 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- University Labor Education Association (ULEA) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Labor Education Information Center (Clearinghouse) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Labor's Stake in World Affairs (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Summary Report on Joint ULEA-Government Agency Conference (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Proposal for Labor Education Programs on Automation and Technological Change (Box 1, Folder 8)
- ULEA (University Labor Education Assn.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Proposal on Labor Education Programs Dealing with Automation and Technological Change (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Proposal for the Establishment of a Labor Education Information Center (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Second Southern Staff Institute (Box 1, Folder 12)
- National Institute of Labor Education (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Summary Report on Nile (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Survey of Adult Education Opportunities for Labor (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Suggested Readings - Ethics and the Politician (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Suggested Readings - Social Issues (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Suggested Readings - Social Conflicts in America (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Suggested Readings - Propaganda and Public Opinion (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Suggested Readings - Politics (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Outline of Courses Fall 1959 - Liberal Arts for Labor Program (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Suggested Readings - The Law and You (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Suggested Readings - Philosophy of Unionism (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Student Reaction (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Suggested Readings - Mass Media (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Outline of Courses Fall 1960 - Liberal Arts for Labor Program (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Violence in the City - An End or a Beginning? (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Distribution of Counselor's Reference Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Continuing Education for Adults (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Inner-City Negro Youth in a Job Training Project (Box 1, Folder 30)
- The House on W. 114th Street (Box 1, Folder 31)
- The Social Background of Political Decision-Makers (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Volume 2 The Training System in the Pipe Trades (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Report of an Evaluation of the Apprenticeship Outreach Program (AOP) (Box 1, Folder 34)
- SER National Office Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- May, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- June, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- February, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- March, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- April, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- January, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- July, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- August, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- September, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- October, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Vouchers - June, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Vouchers - May, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- April, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- March, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Vouchers - January, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- April, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- June, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- May, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- January, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- February, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- March, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- June, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- July, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Bills - August, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- September, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- October, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- November, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- December, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- January Vouchers (Box 2, Folder 29)
- February Vouchers (Box 2, Folder 30)
- March, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- April Vouchers (Box 2, Folder 32)
- May Vouchers (Box 2, Folder 33)
- November, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- December, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- NILE Survey of Adult Education - Union Questionnaires (Natl & Intl) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- NILE Survey of Adult Education - Local Unions Quest. - correspondence (Box 3, Folder 2)
- National Institute of Labor Education at the American University (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Survey of Adult Education - Junior Colleges (Box 3, Folder 4)
- NILE Dissolution (Box 3, Folder 5)
- NILE (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Materials Center Library - Subject Matter, Outlines (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Proposal on Labor Education Programs Dealing with Automation (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Report National Institute of Labor Education, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NILE Survey of Adult Education - State Central Fed. Questionnaires: Lists, Correspondence., etc. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- The Implications of College-Centered Labour Education (Box 3, Folder 11)
- A Summary of the Role of Third Parties in Labor-Management Cooperative Endeavors (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Proposal for Long-Term Non-Residential Study Institutes for Trade Union Leadership (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Amended By-Laws of The National Institute of Labor Education (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Survey of Adult Education Opportunities for Labor, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Materials Center - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Materials Center - Inquiries (Box 3, Folder 17)
- NILE Survey of Adult Education - Univ. Questionnaires: Correspondence., Lists (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Carbon of Final Copy Survey Report (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Preface to Tabulation of Returns on Library Services Questionnaire (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Committee on NILE's Future, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Scope and Contents
  November
- Clearing House (Box 3, Folder 22)
- U.L.E.A. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Pre-Retirement Education Among Labor Unions in the United States (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Final Report OMAT Project P 3-63 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Greater Washington Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO (Box 3, Folder 26)
- New Approaches To Mental Health Treatment for Labor and Low Income Groups (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Proposal for Education, Research, Action Projects on Labor and the Problems of Urbanism (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Proposal for Long-Term Non-Residential Study Institutes for Trade Union Leadership (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Residential Study Institutes for Trade Union Staff (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Proposal on Human Relations Education within Labor Organizations (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Proposal for Labor Education Programs on Automation and Technological Change (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Preliminary Proposals for a Labor-Federal Government Partnership for Improving Health Care (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Clearinghouse (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Roytype Carbon Sets (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Financial Materials (Box 3, Folder 36)